<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Technology - Category - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/categories/technology/</link><description>Technology - Category - JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 11:53:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/categories/technology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FRM Part Ⅰ: Foundations of Risk Management</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230504_frm-part1-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 11:53:59 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230504_frm-part1-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Fundamentals of Risk Management is Chapter 1 of Part 1 for the FRM exam. This chapter primarily covers the foundational knowledge, theories and best practices related to the subject of risk management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Financial Risk Manager Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230402_frm-intro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 16:46:46 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230402_frm-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Financial Risk Manager (FRM) Certification is the true standard for educational excellence in risk management and a gateway to achieving new career heights in the risk profession.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DaVinci Resolve Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230321_davinci-resolve-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 21:31:07 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230321_davinci-resolve-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>DaVinci Resolve is the world’s only solution that combines editing, color correction, visual effects, motion graphics and audio post production all in one software tool! Its elegant, modern interface is fast to learn and easy for new users, yet powerful for professionals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spring Boot Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230226_springboot-intro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 10:54:29 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230226_springboot-intro/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring based Applications that you can &ldquo;just run&rdquo;. Spring Boot takes an opinionated view of building production-ready Spring applications. Favors convention over configuration and is designed to get you up and running as quickly as possible.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Mastering Maven: Advanced Techniques and Best Practices</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230212_mastering-maven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 17:45:04 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230212_mastering-maven/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This article delves into advanced techniques and best practices for using Maven, a popular build automation tool for Java projects. Topics covered include module development and design, dependency management, aggregation and inheritance, property management, and multi-environment configuration and deployment. Whether you&rsquo;re a seasoned Maven user or just getting started, this article will provide valuable insights to streamline your development process and improve your project&rsquo;s overall quality.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Spring Java Basic Conception Sharing</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230118_spring-java-sharing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 20:05:09 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230118_spring-java-sharing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spring makes programming Java quicker, easier, and safer. Spring’s focus on speed, simplicity, and productivity has made it the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular Java framework. Spring works on microservices, reactive, cloud, web apps, serverless, event driven, and batch services.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>