<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hive - Tag - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/hive/</link><description>Hive - Tag - JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:54:16 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/hive/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spark Performance Tuning</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20220719_spark-optimization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:54:16 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20220719_spark-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spark SQL is the top active component in spark 3.0 release. Most of the resolved tickets are for Spark SQL. These enhancements benefit all the higher-level libraries, including structured streaming and MLlib, and higher level APIs, including SQL and DataFrames. Various related optimizations are added in latest release.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HDFS: Parquet Format</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20201215_parquet-format/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 10:47:59 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20201215_parquet-format/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apache Parquet is designed for efficient as well as performant flat columnar storage format of data compared to row based files like CSV or TSV files. Parquet uses the record shredding and assembly algorithm which is superior to simple flattening of nested namespaces. Parquet is optimized to work with complex data in bulk and features different ways for efficient data compression and encoding types. This approach is best especially for those queries that need to read certain columns from a large table. Parquet can only read the needed columns therefore greatly minimizing the IO.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hive Key Points</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20200615_hive-key-point/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 09:26:00 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20200615_hive-key-point/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hive is a Hadoop-based data warehouse tool that maps structured data files into a database table and provides complete SQL query functionality that converts SQL statements into MapReduce tasks for execution. It is very suitable for statistical analysis of data warehouse.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>