<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Linux - Tag - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Linux - Tag - JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:56:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/linux/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automated Deployment of SpringBoot with Jenkins and Docker</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240308_automated-deploy-jenkins-docker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:56:44 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240308_automated-deploy-jenkins-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Explore the power of Jenkins and Docker for automating the deployment of your SpringBoot projects. This blog post walks through integrating these tools to create a seamless CI/CD pipeline, enabling you to build, test, and deploy your applications as containerized services with ease, enhancing your DevOps skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker Overview for Getting Started</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240307_docker-quick-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 10:39:35 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240307_docker-quick-start/</guid><description>&lt;p>Docker takes containerization a step further by providing additional encapsulation for file systems, network interconnections, process isolation, and more. Greatly simplifies the creation and maintenance of containers, making Docker technology more lightweight and faster compared to virtual machine technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GDB debug guide</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20190304_gdb-debug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20190304_gdb-debug/</guid><description>&lt;p>GDB is a powerful program debugging tool based on command line under UNIX/LINUX operating system released by GNU Source Organization. For a C/C ++ programmer working on Linux, GDB is an essential tool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HugePages</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20190203_huge-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 13:04:09 -0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20190203_huge-pages/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reduce page tables by increasing the size of operating system pages to avoid fast table misses. Large page memory optimizer is designed for malloc mechanism, which means allocating large pages to increase TLB hit ratio.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>