<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>java on JerrysBlog</title>
    <link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in java on JerrysBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 15:56:36 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final 关键字: Final Key Word In Java</title>
      <link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/post/20200526finalkeywordinjava/finalkeywordinjava/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 15:56:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/post/20200526finalkeywordinjava/finalkeywordinjava/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Final key word no doubt be mentioned most time in Java language. There are some points about final key word. First of all, final key word can modify three objects: first is modify variables, second is modify way, third is modify class.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Keyword in Java</title>
      <link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/post/20200122javastatic/javastatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 11:20:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/post/20200122javastatic/javastatic/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The static keyword can be used for variables, methods, code blocks, and inner classes to indicate that a particular member belongs only to a class itself, and not to an object of that class.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow Copy and Deep Copy in JAVA</title>
      <link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/post/20191229copyinjava/copyinjava/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 22:14:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/post/20191229copyinjava/copyinjava/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Cloning is a process of creating an exact copy of an existing object in the memory. In java, clone() method of java.lang.Object class is used for cloning process. This method creates an exact copy of an object on which it is called through field-by-field assignment and returns the reference of that object. Not all the objects in java are eligible for cloning process. The objects which implement Cloneable interface are only eligible for cloning process. Cloneable interface is a marker interface which is used to provide the marker to cloning process. Click here to see more info on clone() method in java.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
