<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>C++ - Tag - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/c++/</link><description>C++ - Tag - JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:01:19 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/c++/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamic link library and static link library</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20190125_dynamic-static-link-library/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:01:19 -0800</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20190125_dynamic-static-link-library/</guid><description>&lt;p>In development, we just need to know that lib is needed at compile time and DLL is needed at run time. If you want to compile source code, lib is all you need. If you want dynamically connected programs to run, you need only a DLL. This article will more clearly understand the difference, generation, use of the two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Makefile Guide</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20180915_makefile-cmakelist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:59:46 -0800</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20180915_makefile-cmakelist/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Makefiles define a set of rules that specify which files need to be compiled first, which files need to be compiled later, which files need to be recompiled, and even more complex functional operations, because makefiles are like Shell scripts that also execute operating system commands. One of the benefits of Makefiles is that they are &ldquo;automatically compiled&rdquo;. The entire project is automatically compiled, greatly improving the efficiency of software development.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Hyperscan: high-performance multiple regex matching library</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20180812_hyperscan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 05:42:44 -0700</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20180812_hyperscan/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hyperscan is a high-performance regular expression matching library from Intel. It is based on the X86 platform based on PCRE prototype development. While supporting most of the syntax of PCRE, Hyperscan adds specific syntax and working modes to ensure its usefulness in real-world network scenarios.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>