<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Spring - Tag - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/spring/</link><description>Spring - Tag - JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:56:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/tags/spring/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automated Deployment of SpringBoot with Jenkins and Docker</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240308_automated-deploy-jenkins-docker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:56:44 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240308_automated-deploy-jenkins-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Explore the power of Jenkins and Docker for automating the deployment of your SpringBoot projects. This blog post walks through integrating these tools to create a seamless CI/CD pipeline, enabling you to build, test, and deploy your applications as containerized services with ease, enhancing your DevOps skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comprehensive Guide to Integrating Swagger with Spring</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230925_swagger-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:46:06 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230925_swagger-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the development process, the interface documentation is a crucial part. It not only facilitates developers in viewing and understanding the functionality and parameters of the interfaces but also helps in coordinating the work between the front-end and back-end development, thereby improving development efficiency. This article will introduce how to use Swagger in Spring Boot to automatically generate interface documentation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spring Boot Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230226_springboot-intro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 10:54:29 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230226_springboot-intro/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring based Applications that you can &ldquo;just run&rdquo;. Spring Boot takes an opinionated view of building production-ready Spring applications. Favors convention over configuration and is designed to get you up and running as quickly as possible.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Mastering Maven: Advanced Techniques and Best Practices</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230212_mastering-maven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 17:45:04 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230212_mastering-maven/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This article delves into advanced techniques and best practices for using Maven, a popular build automation tool for Java projects. Topics covered include module development and design, dependency management, aggregation and inheritance, property management, and multi-environment configuration and deployment. Whether you&rsquo;re a seasoned Maven user or just getting started, this article will provide valuable insights to streamline your development process and improve your project&rsquo;s overall quality.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Spring Java Basic Conception Sharing</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230118_spring-java-sharing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 20:05:09 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230118_spring-java-sharing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spring makes programming Java quicker, easier, and safer. Spring’s focus on speed, simplicity, and productivity has made it the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular Java framework. Spring works on microservices, reactive, cloud, web apps, serverless, event driven, and batch services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SpringMVC Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20220914_springmvc-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:38:27 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20220914_springmvc-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spring MVC is a module in the Spring framework that helps you build web applications. It is a framework that helps you build web applications in a clean and modular way, by providing a structure for request handling and a model-view-controller design pattern.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>