<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/posts/</link><description>All Posts | JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:56:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automated Deployment of SpringBoot with Jenkins and Docker</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240308_automated-deploy-jenkins-docker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:56:44 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240308_automated-deploy-jenkins-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Explore the power of Jenkins and Docker for automating the deployment of your SpringBoot projects. This blog post walks through integrating these tools to create a seamless CI/CD pipeline, enabling you to build, test, and deploy your applications as containerized services with ease, enhancing your DevOps skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker Overview for Getting Started</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240307_docker-quick-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 10:39:35 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240307_docker-quick-start/</guid><description>&lt;p>Docker takes containerization a step further by providing additional encapsulation for file systems, network interconnections, process isolation, and more. Greatly simplifies the creation and maintenance of containers, making Docker technology more lightweight and faster compared to virtual machine technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't Waste Your Time Learning Everything</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240125_dontlearneverything/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 22:17:08 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240125_dontlearneverything/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Motivated by this <a href="https://waylonwalker.com/don-t-waste-your-time-learning-everything/?continueFlag=7f3df31b2da359a56804de8af1e39c8f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">post</a> that was itself inspired by this <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/activity-6633818327070326784--Ksl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">LinkedIn post</a>. This LinkedIn post say  Stick to Python and C++, Swift for TensorFlow was nice but it&rsquo;s pretty much dead, and all other languages who are too pretty, academic, lonely and dying</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Speed Up Your Site with a CDN: Content Delivery Network Essentials</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240113_cdn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 08:08:13 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20240113_cdn/</guid><description>&lt;p>One scenario where I need a CDN is for dynamically requesting static JavaScript files on my website. Hosting these large JS files myself would significantly impact my bandwidth usage since my host charges based on traffic volume. Using a CDN helps solve this issue by distributing requests across its worldwide network of data centers. Not only does this improve access speeds by caching files closer to users, it also reduces my origin server load and bandwidth costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Year in Moments: 2023 Video Blog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231231_2023-summary-video/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 11:12:39 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231231_2023-summary-video/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Throughout the year, I captured short video clips documenting my travels, adventures, and life events using my camera. For summaries of my 2023 photos, please check out: <a href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/gallery/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "><i class="fa-solid fa-images fa-fw" aria-hidden="true"></i>&nbsp;jerrysmd.github.io/gallery</a> And to read recaps of the books I enjoyed in 2023: <a href="https://jerrysmd.notion.site/c36b33378ab44eaa8a4e0d51acb419cd?v=f866caf0636341839c3ddd977cbb4bfe&amp;pvs=4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "><i class="fa-solid fa-book-bookmark fa-fw" aria-hidden="true"></i>&nbsp;jerrysmd.notion.site</a></p>]]></description></item><item><title>Striking a Balance Between Speed and Compression Ratio: The Relationship Between Compression Algorithms and Formats</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231230_compression-algorithms-and-formats/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:55:12 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231230_compression-algorithms-and-formats/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some common compression formats include zip, rar, and 7z. Common compression algorithms include gzip, brotli, zstd, lz4, pigz, isa-l, and pzstd. However, what are the relationships between these? How can one strike a balance between compression speed and ratio? What is the relationship between compression algorithms and formats?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>