<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/posts/</link><description>All Posts | JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 07:13:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tracking SQLite Database Changes in Git</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231103_track-sqlite-changes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 07:13:59 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231103_track-sqlite-changes/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>SQLite stores data in binary. If you run <code>cat mydb.sqlite</code>, you&rsquo;ll see a bunch of gibberish that doesn&rsquo;t resemble structured data at all. If you want to track changes and updates to a database using Git, you won&rsquo;t be able to see full diffs by default.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Vector Databases: Comparison for Semantic Search and Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231007_vector-database/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 10:29:03 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20231007_vector-database/</guid><description>&lt;p>In an era where semantic search and retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) are redefining our online interactions, the backbone supporting these advancements is often overlooked: vector databases. If you&amp;rsquo;re diving into applications like large language models, RAG, or any platform leveraging semantic search.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comprehensive Guide to Integrating Swagger with Spring</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230925_swagger-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:46:06 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230925_swagger-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the development process, the interface documentation is a crucial part. It not only facilitates developers in viewing and understanding the functionality and parameters of the interfaces but also helps in coordinating the work between the front-end and back-end development, thereby improving development efficiency. This article will introduce how to use Swagger in Spring Boot to automatically generate interface documentation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chart of Ionizing Radiation Doses Absorbed by Individuals</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230824_radiation-dose-chart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 21:50:17 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230824_radiation-dose-chart/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is a chart of the ionizing radiation dose a person can absorb from various sources. The unit for absorbed dose is &ldquo;Sievert&rdquo; (Sv), and measures the effect a dose of radiation will have on the cells of the body. One sievert (all at once) will make you sick, and too many more will kill you, but we safely absorb small amounts of natural radiation daily.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Blender: A Powerful and Flexible Software for 3D Design and Rendering</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230823_blender-modeling-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 21:54:46 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230823_blender-modeling-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blender is the free and open source 3D creation suite. It supports the entirety of the 3D pipeline—modeling, rigging, animation, simulation, rendering, compositing and motion tracking, even video editing and game creation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FRM Part Ⅰ: Quantitative Analysis</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230702_frm-part1-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 14:26:10 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230702_frm-part1-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Quantitative Analysis is Chapter 2 of Part 1 for the FRM exam. This chapter primarily covers probability and statistics, hypothesis testing and estimation, time series analysis, risk management and portfolio management, and derivatives and risk models.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>