<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - JerrysBlog</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/posts/</link><description>All Posts | JerrysBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 21:50:17 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jerrysmd.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chart of Ionizing Radiation Doses Absorbed by Individuals</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230824_radiation-dose-chart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 21:50:17 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230824_radiation-dose-chart/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is a chart of the ionizing radiation dose a person can absorb from various sources. The unit for absorbed dose is &ldquo;Sievert&rdquo; (Sv), and measures the effect a dose of radiation will have on the cells of the body. One sievert (all at once) will make you sick, and too many more will kill you, but we safely absorb small amounts of natural radiation daily.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Blender 3D Modeling</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230823_bleander-modeling-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 21:54:46 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230823_bleander-modeling-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blender is the free and open source 3D creation suite. It supports the entirety of the 3D pipeline—modeling, rigging, animation, simulation, rendering, compositing and motion tracking, even video editing and game creation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FRM Part Ⅰ: Foundations of Risk Management</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230504_frm-part1-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 11:53:59 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230504_frm-part1-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Fundamentals of Risk Management is Chapter 1 of Part 1 for the FRM exam. This chapter primarily covers the foundational knowledge, theories and best practices related to the subject of risk management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Financial Risk Manager Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230402_frm-intro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 16:46:46 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230402_frm-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Financial Risk Manager (FRM) Certification is the true standard for educational excellence in risk management and a gateway to achieving new career heights in the risk profession.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DaVinci Resolve Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230321_davinci-resolve-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 21:31:07 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230321_davinci-resolve-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>DaVinci Resolve is the world’s only solution that combines editing, color correction, visual effects, motion graphics and audio post production all in one software tool! Its elegant, modern interface is fast to learn and easy for new users, yet powerful for professionals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spring Boot Introduction</title><link>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230226_springboot-intro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 10:54:29 +0800</pubDate><author/><guid>https://jerrysmd.github.io/20230226_springboot-intro/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Spring Boot makes it easy to create stand-alone, production-grade Spring based Applications that you can &ldquo;just run&rdquo;. Spring Boot takes an opinionated view of building production-ready Spring applications. Favors convention over configuration and is designed to get you up and running as quickly as possible.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>